Christopher Hedlund

Hillsboro, OH | christopher.m.hedlund@gmail.com | 443.417.3490

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-hedlund-a6013b8a | GitHub: https://github.com/swedishkinda

Portfolio: https://swedishkinda.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary Web Developer with a passion for front-end development. Experience building websites with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and jQuery from start to finish and seeing strong outcomes when deploying. Adapts well to diverse working environments and collaborating with teams. Brings experience obtained through meticulous design. Prepared to excel in solving complex problems.

SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript ES5/ES6, Node.js, jQuery, API's, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Flexbox.

Databases: Mongo, MSSQL, FireBase, MySQL, and PostgreSQL. Miscellaneous: Microsoft Office, Git/Github, Adobe Suite.

PROJECTS

Pill Tracker: https://github.com/swedishkinda/Pill Tracker | https://github.com/swedishkinda/Pill | https://github.com/swedishkinda/Pill | https://github.com/swedishkinda/Pill

- An app that someone could use to keep track of their medications and when they need a refill.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, and PostgreSQL. Npms I used are Express, ejs, and pg. For styling I used Bootstrap and Flexbox.

My Chef: https://github.com/swedishKinda/My-Chef2 https://swedishkinda.github.io/My-Chef2

- JavaScript application that essentially returns a list of drink or meal recipes based on a given ingredient.
- Technologies: AJAX calls to two separate API's, JQuery library for "Slick" carousel, and "modal" alerts.

ED SITE: https://github.com/swedishKinda/Educational Site https://swedishkinda.github.io/Educational Site

- An educational website with different kinds of interactives.
- **Technologies:** Bootstrap, Flexbox, JavaScript ES6, ¡Query, and Slick.

EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2024 **Accelerate Education**

Front-End Web Developer

- Develop websites to be used in online learning environments.
- Display in depth knowledge of jQuery, JavaScript ES5/ES6, HTML5, CSS3, and Adobe Suite.

Mar. 2015 - Current DoorDash

Associate/Driver

US Aquatics: Beltsville, MD Apr. 2011- Mar. 2015

Regional Manager (Philadelphia Area)

- Interacted with clients to ensure quality customer service. And worked with local governmental operations to see that all standards are met.
- Performed the ability to work independently without direct oversight, but in an overall team environment.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Bootcamp, Philadelphia, PA

Oct. 2019

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development

University of Maryland, Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

Dec. 2007

Mechanical Engineering and Environmental Science